Guide to the Department of History, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of History, Yale University, records
1922-2010
RU 591
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
113
(111 boxes)
The records consist of annual reports, correspondence, recommendations, memoranda, course evaluations and committee and program files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of History. Topics include administration and finances; curriculum planning and programs; faculty appointments; fellowships; graduate student admissions; and the 1998 departmental reunion.
Yale University. Department of History
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of annual reports, correspondence, recommendations, personnel files, promotion files, memoranda, course evaluations and committee and program files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of History. Topics include administration and finances; curriculum planning and programs; faculty appointments; fellowships; graduate student admissions; and the 1998 departmental reunion.
.
History -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Departments; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of History
- Records, 1922-1959; Accession 1960-A-002 (Box 1–22)
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  No online inventory available. Paper inventory available in repository.
- Records concerning graduate studies issues, 1990-1992; Accession 1993-A-092 (Box 1)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2027
- Records, circa 1940-1987; Accession 1997-A-080
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022
  - Budget, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - One year savings, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Endowment fund programs correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Teaching fellows budget, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budget (salaries), 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Payroll confirmations, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Teaching fellows budget, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - One year appointments, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Payroll confirmations, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budget, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Teaching fellows, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Reappointments and promotions, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Payroll confirmation notices, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - One year savings, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Budget (correspondence), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Budget, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Teaching fellows, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Predicted leaves, vacancies, and officerships, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Budget, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
  - Budget (salaries), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Provost; Ellen Ryerson, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Block I, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Blocks II and III, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Budget correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Payroll confirmation, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Budget, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Budget, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Status report and requests, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Budget, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Budget, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Budget, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - Targets of opportunity, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Department of history needs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Budget, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Teaching fellows, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Budget preparation, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Budget, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Budget, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Budget correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Departmental resources, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Copies of procedure report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Event poster, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52A)
  - Japan-United States Friendship Commission; Annual report, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Silverman, Jason H., publications, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Graduate school commencement programs, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History department chair; Smith, Gaddis; Administrative and vital records, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Appointments, reappointments, and promotions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Historical Association (AHA) newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Committee report (parts I and II), Undated (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Predicted leaves, officerships, and vacancies (parts I and II), Undated (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - United States (U.S.) Western, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American Western History search committee, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - History department data, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Annual report, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chairman's file, Ad Hoc committee, promotion of Turner, Frank, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Latin America, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Modern English and Continental Intellectual History (position of Turner, Frank), 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - History of technology, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chairman's letter to Emeriti, 1985 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Affirmative Action program, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Computer center representative, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Tobin committee report (on faculty appointments), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Economic status of the faculty, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Reply to Provost's memo, 1979 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Achieving Financial Equilibrium at Yale, a Report on the Budget, 1977 December (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Provost's Advisory Committee on fringe benefits, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Long range planning, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Committee on special programs in the arts, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Graduate school alumni fund (parts I and II), Undated (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
  - Alternate careers for Humanities PH.D.s, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Advisory committee for "career options", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Departmental procedures report, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Eighteenth-century studies pamphlet, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Council of chairmen, summer, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Council of chairmen, spring, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Council of chairmen, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Contributions to interdisciplinary programs, June 30, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Judaic studies, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Alfred P. Sloan foundation grant, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wage and salary administration, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Economics department, fall supplement information, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Teaching appointments, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Part-time assistant instructor, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General ledger (parts I, II, and III), 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - Middlekauff, R., Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General ledger, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General ledger (parts I and II), 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - General ledger (parts I, II, and III), 1966-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
  - (first balance), 1988 June (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - (second balance), 1988 June (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - (third balance), 1988 June (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1988 July (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1988 August (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1988 September (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1988 October (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1988 November (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1988 December (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1989 January (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1989 February (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1989 March (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1989 April (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1989 May (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - H. Miskimin, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Provost, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Jewish History, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - African History, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Center, new chair, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Divinity school committee, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chinese Science/summers, 1985 August 26 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Legal History file, 1986 February 4 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - International Communism and Eastern Europe, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Latin American studies, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - British History, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Humanities Advisory Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Computer project Eli, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Andrews Society, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Andrews study, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Grad student support, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Undergraduate Major, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Directed Studies, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Spence, Jonathan D., 1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - History department, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - History department, administrative records, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Faculty replacement, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Russian History, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Dean's Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Kotkin, Stephen, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Graduate students and courses, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - History department, administrative records, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Annual report, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Committees, responsibilities, etc., 1987 September (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 1989 spring (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Summer addresses, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Schedule sheets
    - 1988 fall (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 1988 spring (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 1987 fall (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Ph.D. in History Reconsidered, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - GWP and annual report, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - History department schedule sheets
    - 1986 fall (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Spring term, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - 1982 spring (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - 1981 fall (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - 1981 spring (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - 1980 fall (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - 1980 spring (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - 1979 fall (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - 1979 spring (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - 1978 fall (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - 1978 spring (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - 1977 fall (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - 1977 spring (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Graduate Alumni Newsletter, Undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Dean's search committee, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Graduate School Alumni day, corrrespondence, news, and events, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Yale University Library, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2A)
  - Library, newspaper holdings, parts I and II (copies 1 and 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Library, sale of rag London Times, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Report of library committee (copies 1 and 2), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Library, document collecting, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Library problems, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Major subjects for the year, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Enrollment statistics, November 7, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Fellow planning, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Payroll confirmations, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - General ledger and budget approvals (part I, II, III, and IV), 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 14-17)
  - Approved budget (1978-1979), July 27, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - British History, applications, and data from other candidates (parts I, II, III, and IV), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 19-22)
  - British History search; Clark, J.D., 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Search letter and responses, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - McLoughlin, William G.; History course approval, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Appplicants for Colonial History, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Yale College Dean search committee, letters received, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Davis conference, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Dichamp, Christiane, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Davis - rebate, Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Rebate - history department, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Administrative assistant, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Secretaries, fall, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Clerical and technical position classification program; generic job descriptions, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Staff secretary, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Secretary 6, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 574A-31, 87636, Honig, 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 574A-31, 88359, Honig, 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 22A)
  - 574A-31, 88493, Head, 1991-1994 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 574A-31, 88588, Cronon, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 574A-31, 87519, Gay, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - First balance, 1995 June (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Second balance, 1995 June (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 1995 June (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 1995 May (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 1995 April (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - 1995 March (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 1995 February (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - 1995 January (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - 1994 December (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - 1994 November (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - 1994 October (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - 1994 September (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - 1994 August (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - 1994 July (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Third balance, 1994 June (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - 1994 June (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - 1994 May (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Alumni records, 1900-1960s (Box 7)
  - 1994 April (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1994 March (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1994 February (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1994 January (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1993 December (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1993 November (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1993 October (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1993 September (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1993 August (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1993 July (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Turner, Ralph, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Cross Campus Library, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Reviews, Circa 1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Articles, review articles, etc..., Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Russian search, blind letters of reference, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Russian search, blind letters, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Russian search, letters of recommendation, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Russian search correspondence, acknowledgment letters, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Curriculum vitae from Kaiser and Ransel, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Commitment, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Commitment, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Computers and Word Processing, 1979-1983 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Summer addresses, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Committee of Undergraduates on the History major, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Advisory committee to Chairman, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Egleston Prize, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Undergraduate major statistics, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Pre-doctoral fellowship, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - 69202, Sherman Kent memorial fund, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - George Washington Egleston Prize, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - History department statistics, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Senior essay policy decisions, Undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Storm window program, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - History at Illinois, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Graduate courses and room assignments, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Data for Harvard correspondence, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Post-doctoral fellow invitations correspondence, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Potential professor candidates, vitae, Undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - History department meeting records, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Andrews Society survey results, January 25, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - The 1988 New England Historical Association book award (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - History department, student advisory committee report, Undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - List of reserve books; Professor Morgan, E.S., 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - History department correspondence, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - History of the Reformation appointment search, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Senior appointments, March 6, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - DeVane Medical award, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Annual appointments, memorandum, and residential college seminars, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Undergraduate enrollment, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - History department data and schedule sheets, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Teaching fellow budget, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - History graduate department data, and correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Accessiblity questionnaire, August 28, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Financial and adjustments correspondence, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Contemporary Communist-ruled societies, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Personnel profile, student appointment forms, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Personnel profile, student appointment forms, 1976-1985 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Graduate colloquium, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Andrews Society, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Budget for teaching by graduate students, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Part-time acting instructors, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Prize teaching fellowships, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Enrollment list, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - History department lists, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - History department lists, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - History department lists, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Faculty list, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Complete department list with office hours, fall, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Department list, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Faculty lists, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Lists of faculty, 1975-1983 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - History department, Anglo-Japanese Alliance, 1980-1988 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Newsletter, 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Alumni registration, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Graduate student seminars, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Supplement programs of study, 1976-1986 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - History teaching fellows, Undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Lists of new faculty and office space, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Graduate and undergraduate prizes, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Resources and services memorandum, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Middle East search committee, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Middle East, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Middle East position, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Cohen, Dr. Michael J., 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 53A)
  - Daly, Dr. Martin, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 54A)
  - Middle Eastern History search, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - French History (parts I and II), 1957-1960 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  - Candidates, American history, 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 15A)
  - Latin American historians, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Military History, 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - European possible candidates, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Candidates in Economic History, 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Personnel, Faculty, Russian History (old) (parts I and II), 1949-1961 (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
  - Personnel, Faculty, Latin American History (parts I and II), 1949-1962 (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
  - Russian scholars, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - African scholars, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - American History scholars, Undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Asian scholars, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - English scholars, Undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Latin America, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Russian Exchange Program, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - History department, annual reception, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - History department meeting, full professors, October 9, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - History department meeting, October 2, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - History department meeting, October 30, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Full professors meeting, November 6, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - History department meeting, November 13, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - History department meeting, November 27, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - History department meeting, December 4, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - History department meeting, December 11, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - History deparment meeting, January 8, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - United Way, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - 1983 July (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - 1983 August (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - 1983 September (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - 1983 October (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - 1983 November (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - 1983 December (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - 1984 January (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - 1984 February (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - 1984 March (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - 1984 April (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - 1984 May (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - 1984 June (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Second balance, 1984 June (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Third balance, 1984 June (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - 1984 July (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - 1984 August (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - 1984 September (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - 1984 October (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - 1984 November (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - 1984 December (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - 1985 January (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - 1985 June (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - 1985 February (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1985 March (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1985 April (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1985 May (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1985 June (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1985 July (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1985 August (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1985 September (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1985 October (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1985 November (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1985 December (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1986 January (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - 1986 February (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - 1986 March (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - 1986 April (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - 1986 May (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - 1986 June (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Policy on freedom of expression, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Yale University Assistance Program, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - American Historical Association (AHA), Chicago, December 27-30, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Assistant Professor, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Graduate school chairmen and DGS, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) summer stipend and scholarship; diplomat seminars, Stanford, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Concilium grants, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - NEH summer seminars for college teachers, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - University directory, graduate students, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Sexual harassment, racial and ethnic harassment (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Affirmative action, Undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Medieval position, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Ahlstrom reception, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Chicano/Boricua studies, 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Africa/Center for African Studies, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Yale Center for International Studies, Middle East, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Turkish History, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Review committees, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Baswell committee: Undergraduate curriculum, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Yale Press, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Possible college seminars, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Yale Undergraduate Forum, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Statistics of Undergraduate Majors, 1973-1982 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Department statistics, 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - British Art Center, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Summer teaching, October 13, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Visiting Faculty Fellow Program, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Yale College Course of Study Committee, Review of department of History, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Joint boards of permanent officers, Undated (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Debate, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Katharine Angell death notice, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 53A)